Finding Aid for the Oliver Cromwell Carmichael Papers
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
- The Series
  - Writings – Essays
    - “State-Supported Colleges for Women in the Higher Education of Women in the United States” (Box 25, Folder 36)
    - “Status of American Higher Education” (Box 25, Folder 37)
    - “Towards Liberal Education” (Box 25, Folder 38)
    - “Tribute to Howard Stephens Hilley, Rhodes Scholar from Kentucky, 1914-1917” (Box 25, Folder 39)
    - “Universidade de Minas Gerais” (Box 25, Folder 40)
    - “The University of Recife” (Box 25, Folder 41)
    - “The Unromantic Side of War” (Box 25, Folder 42)
    - “What Constitutes an Educated Man” (Box 25, Folder 43)
    - “Women and Higher Education” (Box 25, Folder 44)
    - (untitled) on American Women (Box 25, Folder 45)
    - (untitled) the American Revolution; Psychology of William James (Box 25, Folder 46)
  - Writings – Reports
    - “Distribution of Rhodes Scholarships 1928–1933” (Box 26, Folder 1)
    - “The Place and Use of the Bible in Religious Education” Executive Committee of Religious Education and Publication of the Presbyterian Church, U.S., 1939 (Box 26, Folder 2)
    - “Memorandum of Measurement of Educational Results”, 1946 (Box 26, Folder 3)
    - For the Board of Trustees, State University of New York at Buffalo, January 28, 1950 (Box 26, Folder 4)
    - “Merger of Long Island Medical College with the State University of New York”, April 5, 1950 (Box 26, Folder 5)
    - “The Development of Sound Graduate Education in the South” A Memorandum to the Carnegie Corporation of New York and Carnegie Foundation for the Advancement of Teaching”, October 13, 1950 (Box 26, Folder 6)
    - “A Statement for the Case of Autherine Lucy for the Board of Trustees of University of Alabama”, 1956 (Box 26, Folder 7)
    - “Statement to Faculty and Students of the University of Alabama”, February 16, 1956 (Box 26, Folder 8)
    - “Notes on Demonstrations: Saturday Night Demonstrations, February 4, 1956” (Box 26, Folder 9)
    - “Working Towards an Effective Board of Trustees”, June 27 1959 (Box 26, Folder 10)
    - “A Three-Year Master’s Degree Program (for New England Board of Higher Education), 1960 (Box 26, Folder 11)
    - “Report to Ford Foundation on Visits to Canadian Universities made July 10-25, 1962” (Box 26, Folder 12)
    - “Report to Ford Foundation on Visits to Canadian Universities”, July 10-25, 1962 (Box 26, Folder 13)
    - “Graduate Work at Wake Forest College” (with R.P. McCutcheon), 1962 (Box 26, Folder 14)
    - “Graduate Education Study Report – Wake Forest College, 1962” (with R.P. McCutcheon) (Box 26, Folder 15)
    - “Some Observations and Comments” (to the North Carolina State Board of Higher Education), January 1964 (Box 26, Folder 16)
    - “Professional Schools in Ohio” (with Harvie Branscomb), 1964 (Box 26, Folder 17)
    - Reports (with Harvie Branscomb) “Professional Schools in Ohio” (to the Carnegie Foundation), 1964 (Box 26, Folder 18)
    - “Glimpses of Europe and Rhodes-Scholar Reunion” (Box 26, Folder 19)
    - “Tentative Plan for a Study of Housing and Family Personnel” (Box 26, Folder 20)
    - “Statement by Oliver C. Carmichael” Re: resignation from the University of Alabama, n.d (Box 26, Folder 21)
    - “Higher Education in Kansas: Report of Findings on Visits to Selected Institutions” (Box 26, Folder 22)
    - “Report of Commission on History and Publicity” (Box 26, Folder 23)
    - “International University Association for the Advancement of Peace”, n.d (Box 26, Folder 24)
    - “Rhodes International Association for the Advancement of Peace”, n.d (Box 26, Folder 25)
    - “Radio Editorial” – n.d.; “ Proposal for British Commonwealth-American Commission on University Education” n.d.; “Comments on Papers by Cooper, Gustad, and Mayhew” (Box 26, Folder 26)
    - “Training of Community College Teachers” with accompanying material, c. 1964; “Year Round Operation of the Colleges and Universities” (Box 26, Folder 27)
  - Writings – Published Articles
    - “Educational Research and Statistics” in School and Society, Vol. 23, no. 582, February 1926 (Box 26, Folder 28)
    - “Liberty versus Security” Southern States Industrial Council, November 1938 (Box 26, Folder 29)
    - “Some Issues in the Higher Learning” reprinted from The Educational Record for, July 1938 (Box 26, Folder 30)
    - “Assets of Southern Progress” reprinted by the Alabama State Chamber of Commerce, October 19, 1939 (Box 26, Folder 31)
    - “America and the Present Crisis” Chamber of Commerce of the United States, May 2, 1940 (Box 26, Folder 32)
    - “The Relation of the Endowed University to Our Democracy” reprinted from Southern Association Quarterly, August 1940 (Box 26, Folder 33)
    - “Liberal Arts versus General Education” reprinted from Southern Association Quarterly, May 1941 (Box 26, Folder 34)
    - “Adapting the Secondary Schools to the Emergency” in The Peabody Reflector, Vol. 16 (1943), no. 1 (Box 26, Folder 35)
    - “The College and the Future” in program of The Inauguration of John Edwin Pomfret as Twenty-first President of the College of William and Mary in Virginia, February 8, 1943 (Box 26, Folder 36)
  - Writings – Published Articles
    - “The Teacher and Educational Results” in The 41st. Annual Report of the Carnegie Foundation for the Advancement of Teaching, 1945 – 46+ (Box 27, Folder 1)
    - “Education for the New Era” in Southern Association Quarterly, May 1946; “Education for the New Era” reprinted from Hispania (Box 27, Folder 2)
    - “More Effective Instruction in Colleges and Universities in the South” reprint of an address before thefifty-first Annual Meeting of the Southern Association of Colleges and Secondary Schools, Memphis, TN, December 12, 1946 (Box 27, Folder 3)
    - “Science and Social Progress” in Think, Vol. 12 (1946), no. 12 (Box 27, Folder 4)
    - “Some Educational Frontiers” reprinted from School and Society, Vol. 68, No. 1761, September 25, 1948 (Box 27, Folder 5)
    - “What Constitutes an Educated Man” in The American Mercury, Vol. LXVI (1948), no. 291 (Box 27, Folder 6)
    - “Report of the President” in The 44th Annual Report of the Carnegie Foundation for the Advancement of Teaching, 1948-49 (Box 27, Folder 7)
    - “Background and Opportunity of the State of New York” published by the State University of New York at Albany, April 4, 1949 (Box 27, Folder 8)
    - “Report of the President” in The 45th Annual Report of the Carnegie Foundation for the Advancement of Teaching, 1949-50 (Box 27, Folder 9)
    - “Education and International Understanding” Occasional Paper No. 53, University of Hawaii, Honolulu, June 1950 (Box 27, Folder 10)
    - “Outlook for the Future” in The Education Digest, Vol. XV, February 1950, no. 6 (Box 27, Folder 11)
    - “America’s Problems and Prospects” in University of Washington Commencement Program, 1951 (Box 27, Folder 12)
    - “The Report of the President” in The 47th Annual Report of the Carnegie Foundation for the Advancement of Teaching, 1951-52 (Box 27, Folder 13)
    - “The Report of the President” reprinted from The Annual Report of Officers of the Foundation for the Year Ended June 30, 1953; The 48th Annual Report of the Carnegie Foundation for the Advancement of Teaching, 1952-53 (Box 27, Folder 14)
    - “A Spaulding Lecture at Yale University” press release for the morning newspapers in New Haven, Connecticut, April 26, 1952 (Box 27, Folder 15)
    - “The University Today” in Michigan Alumnus, Vol. LIX, December 6, 1952, number 10 (Box 27, Folder 16)
    - “Status of American Higher Education” in The Carnegie Foundation for the Advancement of Teaching, Committees of Educational Inquiry Conference, Skytop, Pennsylvania, May 2-3, 1952 (Box 27, Folder 17)
    - “The Roots of Higher Education in Minnesota” in Minnesota History, Vol. 34, no. 3, Autumn 1954 (Box 27, Folder 18)
    - “Liberal Education” in the Fifty-first Annual Report of the Carnegie Foundation for the Advancement of Teaching, 1955-56 (Box 27, Folder 19)
    - Review “Higher Education – The Year Book of Education 1959” in Harvard Education Review (Box 27, Folder 20)
  - Writings – Book Manuscripts – Universities: Commonwealth and American
    - Comments on Carmichael’s book (from unknown writer) (Box 28, Folder 1)
    - Publishers statements (Box 28, Folder 2)
    - Notes (Box 28, Folder 3)
    - Notes (Box 28, Folder 4)
    - Notes (Box 28, Folder 5)
    - Notes (Box 28, Folder 6)
    - Notes and outlines (Box 28, Folder 7)
    - chapter draft (Box 28, Folder 8)
    - chapter draft (Box 28, Folder 9)
    - Chapter 2 (Box 28, Folder 10)
    - chapter draft on “India and Pakistan” (Box 28, Folder 11)
    - Appendix II-Footnotes (Box 28, Folder 12)
    - statistics (Box 28, Folder 13)
    - statistics (Box 28, Folder 14)
    - Preface and introduction (Box 28, Folder 15)
    - Preface and introduction (Box 28, Folder 16)
    - Chapters I-III (Box 28, Folder 17)
    - Chapters IV – V (Box 28, Folder 18)
    - Chapters VI – VIII (Box 28, Folder 19)
    - Chapters IX – X (Box 28, Folder 20)
    - Chapter XI (Box 28, Folder 21)
    - Chapters XII – XIII (Box 28, Folder 22)
    - Chapter 14 – handwritten (Box 28, Folder 23)
    - Chapter XIV and Appendix (Box 28, Folder 24)
  - Writings – Book Manuscripts – Universities: Commonwealth and American
    - Chapter I – typescript (Box 29, Folder 1)
    - Chapter II – typescript (Box 29, Folder 2)
    - Chapter III – typescript (Box 29, Folder 3)
    - Chapter IV – typescript (Box 29, Folder 4)
    - Chapter V – typescript (Box 29, Folder 5)
    - Chapter VI – typescript (Box 29, Folder 6)
    - Chapter VII – typescript (Box 29, Folder 7)
    - Chapter VIII – typescript (Box 29, Folder 8)
    - Chapter IX – typescript (Box 29, Folder 9)
    - Chapter X – typescript (Box 29, Folder 10)
    - Chapter XI – typescript (Box 29, Folder 11)
    - Chapter XII – typescript (Box 29, Folder 12)
    - Chapter XIII – typescript (Box 29, Folder 13)
    - Chapter XIV-typescript (Box 29, Folder 14)
    - Bibliography (Box 29, Folder 15)
    - Typescript of the entire book (Box 29, Folder 16)
  - Writings – Book Manuscripts - Universities: Commonwealth and American
    - Typescript of the entire book (Box 30, Folder 1)
    - Typescript of the entire book (Box 30, Folder 2)
    - Typescript of the entire book (Box 30, Folder 3)
  - Writings – Book Manuscripts
    - The Changing Role of Higher Education – speech to be published by Kappa Delta Pi, 1949 (Box 31, Folder 1)
    - The University of Tomorrow (unfinished) – Outline and Introduction – typescript (Box 31, Folder 2)
  - Writings – Book Manuscripts – Higher Education: the British Commonwealth and the U.S.
    - Contents (Box 31, Folder 3)
    - Introduction (Box 31, Folder 4)
    - Chapter I (Box 31, Folder 5)
    - Chapter I (2 copies) (Box 31, Folder 6)
    - Chapter I (revised – 2 copies) (Box 31, Folder 7)
    - Chapter I (revised) (Box 31, Folder 8)
    - Chapter II (Box 31, Folder 9)
    - Chapter II (revised) (Box 31, Folder 10)
    - Chapter II (2 copies) (Box 31, Folder 11)
    - Chapter III (Box 31, Folder 12)
    - Chapter III (2 copies) (Box 31, Folder 13)
    - Chapter IV (Box 31, Folder 14)
    - Chapter IV (2 copies) (Box 31, Folder 15)
    - Chapter V (2 copies) (Box 31, Folder 16)
    - Chapter V (2 copies) (Box 31, Folder 17)
  - Writings – Book Manuscripts - Higher Education: the British Commonwealth and the U.S.
    - Chapter VI (2 copies) (Box 32, Folder 1)
    - Chapter VI (2 copies) (Box 32, Folder 2)
    - Chapter VII (2 copies) (Box 32, Folder 3)
    - Chapter VIII (Box 32, Folder 4)
    - Chapter VII (2 copies) (Box 32, Folder 5)
    - Chapter IX (Box 32, Folder 6)
    - Chapter IX (2 copies) (Box 32, Folder 7)
    - Chapter X (Box 32, Folder 8)
    - Chapter X (revised) (Box 32, Folder 9)
    - Chapter XI (Box 32, Folder 10)
    - Chapter XII (Box 32, Folder 11)
    - Chapter XII (revised) (Box 32, Folder 12)
    - Chapter XIII (Box 32, Folder 13)
    - Chapter XIII (revised) (Box 32, Folder 14)
    - Chapter XIV (Box 32, Folder 15)
    - Chapter XV (Box 32, Folder 16)
    - Bibliography (Box 32, Folder 17)
  - Writings – Book Manuscripts – Graduate Education: A Critique and a Program -Typescript
    - Title pages, Preface, and Introduction (Box 33, Folder 1)
    - Chapter I (Box 33, Folder 2)
    - Chapter II (Box 33, Folder 3)
    - Chapter III (Box 33, Folder 4)
    - Chapter IV (Box 33, Folder 5)
    - Chapter V (Box 33, Folder 6)
    - Chapter VI (Box 33, Folder 7)
    - Chapter VII (Box 33, Folder 8)
    - Chapter VIII (Box 33, Folder 9)
    - Chapter IX (Box 33, Folder 10)
    - Chapter X (Box 33, Folder 11)
    - Part 2 - Introduction (Box 33, Folder 12)
    - Chapter XI (Box 33, Folder 13)
    - Chapter XII (Box 33, Folder 14)
    - Chapter XIII (Box 33, Folder 15)
    - Appendix and Index (Box 33, Folder 16)
    - Typescript of the Book, Corrected copy (Box 33, Folder 17)
  - Writings – Book Manuscripts – Graduate Education: A Critique and a Program-Typescripts and Galleys
    - Typescript of book copy (Box 34, Folder 1)
    - Typescript - General outline (Box 34, Folder 2)
    - Typescript - Preface (Box 34, Folder 3)
    - Typescript - Introduction (Box 34, Folder 4)
    - Typescript - Chapter I (Box 34, Folder 5)
    - Typescript - Chapter II (Box 34, Folder 6)
    - Typescript - Chapter III (Box 34, Folder 7)
    - Typescript - Chapter IV (Box 34, Folder 8)
    - Typescript - Part II – a Program – Introduction (Box 34, Folder 9)
    - Typescript - Chapter XI (Box 34, Folder 10)
    - Galleys – Contents, Preface, Bibliography, Index (Box 34, Folder 11)
    - Galleys – Preface, Introduction (Box 34, Folder 12)
    - Galleys – Part I – Preface, Introduction, and Chapter I (Box 34, Folder 13)
    - Galleys – Part I – Chapters 1-4 (Box 34, Folder 14)
    - Galleys – Part I – Chapters 2-4 (Box 34, Folder 15)
    - Galleys – Part I – Chapters 5-10 (Box 34, Folder 16)
    - Galleys – Part I – Chapters 5-10 (Box 34, Folder 17)
    - Galleys – Part II – Chapters 11-13, Bibliography, Index (Box 34, Folder 18)
    - Galleys – Part II – Introduction, Chapters 11-13, Bibliography and Index (Box 34, Folder 19)
  - Writings – Book Manuscripts – Graduate Education: A Critique and a Program
    - Introduction – holograph copy (Box 35, Folder 1)
    - Chapter I – holograph copy (Box 35, Folder 2)
    - Chapter 5 – holograph copy (Box 35, Folder 3)
    - Chapter 6 – holograph and typescript copies (Box 35, Folder 4)
    - Chapter 7 – holograph copy (Box 35, Folder 5)
    - Chapter 8 – holograph copy (Box 35, Folder 6)
    - Part II – Introduction – holograph copy (Box 35, Folder 7)
    - Chapter 10 – holograph copy (Box 35, Folder 8)
    - Chapter 13 – holograph copy (Box 35, Folder 9)
    - Graduate Education: a Critique and a Program – reviews, awards, notices – American Council on Education, 1962 (Box 35, Folder 10)
  - Writings – Book Manuscripts/Reports/ Other
    - Graduate Education in the United States – “The Nature of the Problem and the Elements in Its Solution” – chapter draft typescript (Box 35, Folder 11)
    - Graduate Education in the United States _ “ Graduate Programs and Problem Areas” – chapter draft typescript (Box 35, Folder 12)
    - “University Education: a Public Enterprise” – holograph copy (Box 35, Folder 13)
    - Adventures in Education – typescripts – table of contents – page 75 (unpublished) (Box 35, Folder 14)
    - Adventures in Education – typescript – pages 76 – 155 (unpublished) (Box 35, Folder 15)
    - Adventures in Education – typescript – pages 156 – 223 (unpublished) (Box 35, Folder 16)
    - Education for All American Children- Education Policies Commission-typescript – Table of Contents – Chapter 1, (1946) (Box 35, Folder 17)
    - Education for All American Children- Education Policies Commission-typescript – Table of Contents – Chapter 2, (1946) (Box 35, Folder 18)
    - Education for All American Children- Education Policies Commission-typescript – Table of Contents – Chapter 3, (1946) (Box 35, Folder 19)
    - Education for All American Children- Education Policies Commission-typescript – Table of Contents – Chapter 4-5, (1946) (Box 35, Folder 20)
  - Writings – Book Manuscripts/Reports/Other
    - Education for All American Children- Education Policies Commission – typescript – Chapter 6, (1946) (Box 36, Folder 1)
    - Education for All American Children- Education Policies Commission – typescript – Chapter 7, (1946) (Box 36, Folder 2)
    - Education for All American Children- Education Policies Commission – “Conference and Personnel”, (April 1947) (Box 36, Folder 3)
    - Education for All American Children – Education Policies Commission – Foreword; “Focus on Values and Techniques”, (April 1947) (Box 36, Folder 4)
    - Education for All American Children – Education Policies Commission – Chapter I “Elementary Schools in Farmville and Oak Hill, State of Columbia, (April 1947) (Box 36, Folder 5)
    - Education for All American Children – Education Policies Commission – Chapter III – the schools of American City, Woodland Park and Pattonsburg, (April 1947) (Box 36, Folder 6)
    - Education for All American Children – Education Policies Commission – Chapter IV – “The Curriculum as Living and Learning”, (April 1947) (Box 36, Folder 7)
    - Education for All American Children – Education Policies Commission - Chapter V – “The Staff Guides Living and Learning”, (April 1947) (Box 36, Folder 8)
    - Education for All American Children – Education Policies Commission - Chapter VI- “Administration Promotes Living and Learning”, (April 1947) (Box 36, Folder 9)
    - Education for All American Children – Education Policies Commission - Chapter VII- “Living and Learning are Community Concerns”, (April 1947) (Box 36, Folder 10)
    - Education for All American Children – Education Policies Commission - typescript (Box 36, Folder 11)
    - The First Business of Our Times – confidential draft, cover – D9, (September 1966) (Box 36, Folder 12)
    - The First Business of Our Times – confidential draft E1 – F17, (September 1966) (Box 36, Folder 13)
    - The First Business of Our Times – confidential draft G1 – H21, (September 1966) (Box 36, Folder 14)
    - The First Business of Our Times – confidential draft I -1 – J33, (September 1966) (Box 36, Folder 15)
    - The First Business of Our Times – confidential draft K-1 – M-4, (September 1966) (Box 36, Folder 16)
    - Fragments (Box 36, Folder 17)
    - Research materials – newspaper clippings - photocopies (Box 36, Folder 18)
  - Writings – Book Manuscripts – Research Materials
    - Research materials (Box 37, Folder 1)
    - Research materials (Box 37, Folder 2)
    - Research materials (Box 37, Folder 3)
    - Research materials (Box 37, Folder 4)
    - Research materials (Box 37, Folder 5)
    - Research materials (Box 37, Folder 6)
    - Research materials (Box 37, Folder 7)
    - Research materials (Box 37, Folder 8)
  - Writings – Book Manuscripts – Research Materials
    - Research materials (Box 38, Folder 1)
    - Research materials (Box 38, Folder 2)
    - Research materials (Box 38, Folder 3)
    - Research materials (Box 38, Folder 4)
    - Research materials (Box 38, Folder 5)
    - Research materials (Box 38, Folder 6)
    - Research materials (Box 38, Folder 7)
    - Research materials (Box 38, Folder 8)
    - Research materials (Box 38, Folder 9)
    - Research materials (Box 38, Folder 10)
    - Research materials (Box 38, Folder 11)
    - Research materials (Box 38, Folder 12)
    - Research materials (Box 38, Folder 13)
    - Research materials (Box 38, Folder 14)
    - Research materials (Box 38, Folder 15)
  - Writings – Addresses/Speeches – Research notes, 1928–1944
    - Notes (Box 39, Folder 1)
    - Notes (Box 39, Folder 2)
    - Notes (Box 39, Folder 3)
    - Notes (Box 39, Folder 4)
    - Notes (Box 39, Folder 5)
    - Notes (Box 39, Folder 6)
    - Notes (Box 39, Folder 7)
    - Notes (Box 39, Folder 8)
    - Notes (Box 39, Folder 9)
    - Notes (Box 39, Folder 10)
    - Notes (Box 39, Folder 11)
    - Notes (Box 39, Folder 12)
    - Notes (Box 39, Folder 13)
    - Notes – medical profession (Box 39, Folder 14)
  - Writings by others – alphabetical by author
    - Allison – Ayers (Box 40, Folder 1)
    - Bell – Berelson (Box 40, Folder 2)
    - Boucher – Butterweck (Box 40, Folder 3)
    - N.E.B. (Box 40, Folder 4)
    - Carmack – Coles (Box 40, Folder 5)
    - Conant – Covelli (Box 40, Folder 6)
    - Davidson – Dunn (Box 40, Folder 7)
    - Eells – Flinn (Box 40, Folder 8)
    - Fox, Melvin J. – Fulbright, J. William (Box 40, Folder 9)
    - Gabriel – Grinter (Box 40, Folder 10)
    - Hansley – Hersey (Box 40, Folder 11)
    - Hobbs – Hutchins (Box 40, Folder 12)
    - Johnson – Koenker (Box 40, Folder 13)
    - Langman – Lunt (Box 40, Folder 14)
  - Writings by others – alphabetical by author
    - McCutcheon – Mott (Box 41, Folder 1)
    - Myers, Edward D. et al. – Education in the Perspective of History – galleys (Box 41, Folder 2)
    - Myers, Edward D. et al. – Education in the Perspective of History – galleys (Box 41, Folder 3)
    - Myers, Edward D. et al. – Education in the Perspective of History – galleys (Box 41, Folder 4)
    - Myers, Edward D. et al. – Education in the Perspective of History – galleys (Box 41, Folder 5)
    - Myers, Edward D. et al. – Education in the Perspective of History – galleys (Box 41, Folder 6)
    - Otto – Rosenzweig (Box 41, Folder 7)
    - Sanford – Stroupe (Box 41, Folder 8)
    - Tead – Totaro (Box 41, Folder 9)
    - Ten Hoor, Marten (Box 41, Folder 10)
    - University of Pittsburgh Press – Young (Box 41, Folder 11)
    - Unidentified (Box 41, Folder 12)
- Biographical/Personal
  - Newspaper Clippings - 1931–1966 – originals
    - 1931 (Box 42, Folder 1)
    - 1934 (Box 42, Folder 2)
    - 1935 (Box 42, Folder 3)
    - 1936 (Box 42, Folder 4)
    - 1937 (Box 42, Folder 5)
    - 1938 (Box 42, Folder 6)
    - 1939 (Box 42, Folder 7)
    - 1940 (Box 42, Folder 8)
    - 1942 (Box 42, Folder 9)
    - 1944 (Box 42, Folder 10)
    - 1945 (Box 42, Folder 11)
    - 1946 (Box 42, Folder 12)
    - 1947 (Box 42, Folder 13)
    - 1948 (Box 42, Folder 14)
    - 1949 (Box 42, Folder 15)
    - 1950 (Box 42, Folder 16)
    - 1951 (Box 42, Folder 17)
    - 1952 (Box 42, Folder 18)
    - 1953-1956 (Box 42, Folder 19)
    - 1957 (Box 42, Folder 20)
    - 1958 (Box 42, Folder 21)
    - 1959 (Box 42, Folder 22)
    - 1960 (Box 42, Folder 23)
    - 1961 (Box 42, Folder 24)
    - 1962 (Box 42, Folder 25)
    - 1963 (Box 42, Folder 26)
    - 1964 (Box 42, Folder 27)
    - 1965 (Box 42, Folder 28)
    - 1966 (Box 42, Folder 29)
    - n.d (Box 42, Folder 30)
    - n.d (Box 42, Folder 31)
  - Biographical/Personal Material
    - Biographical information (Resumes) (Box 43, Folder 1)
    - Biographical information (resumes) (Box 43, Folder 2)
    - Resumes of others (Box 43, Folder 3)
    - Schedules for OCC, 1957-1960 (Box 43, Folder 4)
    - Biographical information (clubs and degrees) (Box 43, Folder 5)
    - Biographical information (Who’s Who in America) (Box 43, Folder 6)
    - Biographical information for Harper and Brothers Publishers; Report background on OCC (Box 43, Folder 7)
    - Biographical information (newspaper clippings) (Box 43, Folder 8)
    - Carmichael’s statement as a candidate for Congress in Alabama, c. 1920 (Box 43, Folder 9)
    - Certificate for the Appointment as Vice-Chairman of the New York State University Commission, July 12, 1946 (Box 43, Folder 10)
    - “Carmichael Selection a Surprise….” In The Crimson-White, University of Alabama, May 5, 1953 (Box 43, Folder 11)
    - Senate Joint Resolution honoring OCC, July 6, 1953 (Box 43, Folder 12)
    - “Carmichael Gives His Last Report as Carnegie Foundation President” press release, November 30, 1953 (Box 43, Folder 13)